[man coughing]
[tires squealing]
[men screaming and yelling]
YOU OKAY?
YEAH, I'M OKAY.
YOU SURE?
YEAH. GO CHECK THE CAR.
GO ON.
[steam hissing]
BUDDY, BUDDY,
ARE YOU OKAY?
FINE, THANKS.
NOW GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME
AND OPEN THE DOOR.
DON'T GO FOR
THE SHOTGUN!
MY LEG!
IT'S BROKEN.
COME HERE!
MOVE!
YOU KNOW
THE ROUTINE
GET YOUR ARMS
BEHIND YOUR BACK!
NOW WALK!
MY LEG!
MOVE ASIDE.
MY ARM.
WHAT'S BROKEN,
YOUR ARM OR YOUR LEG?
YOUR FACE.
COME ON,
LET'S GO!
TAKE IT EASY,
TAKE IT EASY.
OKAY... LET
THEM ALL GO.
BRING HIM BACK HERE!
DO IT!
COME ON, CALM DOWN,
CALM DOWN!
[men clamoring to get out]
SHIT! SHIT!
STEAL A CAR,
GO TO HELL.
SHIT!
HEY, BUDDY!
[man whoops]
LET'S GO,
COME ON!
I TOLD YOU I'D GET
YOU OUT AND I DID IT.
OH, GOD.
OH, MY GOD!
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN
ME IN JAIL, NOT YOU.
IT SHOULD HAVE
BEEN ME.
DO YOU FORGIVE ME?
I FORGIVE YOU,
BILLY.
I'M GLAD, MAN.
I... I COULDN'T...
I COULDN'T HAVE THAT
HANGING OVER ME
FOR THE REST
OF MY LIFE.
BILLY...
YOU THINK THAT
OUGHT TO HOLD YOU?
SOME WHISKEY.
WOULDN'T SELL MEAT
WITHOUT WHISKEY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
UP THIS WAY?
HUNTING.
IN A SUIT?
WHAT KIND OF HUNTING?
PINK FLAMINGOS.
Radio announcer: State Police have
rounded up 12 of the 18 prisoners
in yesterday's
prison bus escape.
The six prisoners
still unaccounted for
are to be considered
possibly armed and dangerous...
YOU EVER SEE ANY PINK FLAMINGOS?
NO, SIR.
NEVER HAVE...
NEVER WILL.
YOU SURE?
YES, SIR.
HOW MUCH?
[music playing
in far distance]
[birds tweeting]
[crickets chirping]
[country music plays
in distance]
[music plays louder]
Girl: DO WE HAVE TO GO NOW?
Woman:
YES.
THANK YOU
FOR THIS MESS.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
HEY, YOU DIDN'T
MAKE YOUR BEDS.
NOPE.
MOMMY, CAN WE
GET ANOTHER DOG?
WE'LL SEE, HONEY.
NIGHT-NIGHT.
NIGHT.
YOU TOO, PAL.
GOOD NIGHT, MOM.
GOOD NIGHT.
SLEEP WELL.
[crickets chirping]
[water running]
[door creaks]
[floorboards creak]
[water continues running]
[floorboard creaks]
[floorboard creaks again]
[water continues running]
[lamp rocks on table]
[gasps]
[door slams]
WHO NAMED GOD "GOD"?
GOD DID.
GOD NAMED GOD "GOD"?
MM-HM.
WHY DIDN'T HE
NAME HIMSELF
TOM OR CHARLIE?
CAN I PUT SALT ON THIS, MOM?
[explosion]
[dishes rattling]
IT'S OKAY.
[glass breaking]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S DYNAMITE
AGAIN?
YES.
IT'S OKAY,
HONEY.
JUST EAT YOUR
BREAKFAST.
Boy: WHERE'S THE SALT, MOM?
DOESN'T NEED ANY SALT, MOOKIE.
COME ON, JUST A LITTLE.
BREE, DID YOU MOVE
THE SALT SHAKER?
NO.
I DON'T BELIEVE THIS.
E.T. TOOK IT.
MOOKIE...
HE DID, HE WAS HERE.
I HEARD HIM.
WHEN?
LAST NIGHT.
E.T. IS MAKE-BELIEVE.
HE IS NOT,
HE WAS HERE.
MOOKIE, YOU'VE
GOT TO STOP
MAKING THINGS UP.
I'M NOT!
YOU ARE!
PLEASE STOP IT!
[quietly]:
"WORLD'S GREATEST DAD."
Man:
Hey, Sam, this is Billy.
Wish I could be there
to split that money with you
but I guess
if you're listening to this
then it's all yours now, right?
Well, you deserve it
being in prison all that time
because of me.
Hey, I wonder
which way I'm headed.
Either way, up or down
I guess I got a 50-50 chance
of meeting Elvis.
How do you like the suit
I picked out for you?
Anyhow, lay low
and don't go getting into things
the way you sometimes do.
Oh, and Sam...
I'm glad I knew you.
[grunting]
[explosion]
[birds chirping frantically]
[knock at door]
COME IN.
OH, COME IN,
LONNIE.
COME IN, COME IN.
I WANT YOU TO MEET
MR. DUNSTON.
LONNIE POOLE.
HE'LL BE
TAKING CARE
OF CERTAIN ASPECTS
OF SECURITY
AND SURVEYING.
HEY, WELL, DON'T MIND ME.
I'VE ALREADY BRIEFED
MR. DUNSTON
ON THE SITUATION HERE.
HOW ARE THINGS GOING
WITH MRS. ANDERSON?
SHE'S HARDHEADED,
BUT WE'LL WORK IT OUT.
WE'RE GOING TO
NEED HER PARCEL
AND THE LEWIS PLACE
NEXT TO HER.
THAT'S 120 ACRES
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE WHOLE
DEVELOPMENT.
I KNOW THAT,
MR. HALE.
WE CAN'T GO FORWARD
WITHOUT THEM.
WHAT'S YOUR SECURITY TRAINING
MR. DUNSTON?
[explosion]
CLEVELAND POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
WHY DID YOU LEAVE?
PICK A CARD.
TAKE IT, TAKE IT.
Dunston:
GO ON, PICK A CARD.
GOT IT?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, PUT IT
BACK IN THE DECK.
[chuckling]
LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
THIS ANDERSON WOMAN,
ARE YOU FUCKING HER?
NONE OF YOUR DAMN BUSINESS.
WHO IS THIS GUY?
I DIDN'T MEAN...
GENTLEMEN, PLEASE.
I DIDN'T MEAN ANYTHING.
I'M SORRY.
OKAY.
IS THAT YOUR CARD?
NO.
NO?
JEEZ, I MUST BE SLIPPING.
LONNIE, WHY DON'T YOU
GO BACK TO WORK?
HEY, GOOD TO MEET YOU, LONNIE.
SORRY
ABOUT THAT.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT TOO OPTIMISTIC
ABOUT OUR YOUNG
FRIEND'S SUCCESS.
SOME OF THESE LANDOWNERS
CAN BE HARD NUTS TO CRACK.
THEN WE USE A HAMMER.
THAT WAS NICE.
IT WAS.
THEY COME TO
SEE YOU AGAIN?
I DON'T WANT TO TALK
ABOUT THIS, LONNIE.
THEY'RE BLASTING
OVER AT THE
BRAEMERS' AGAIN.
THEY'RE TURNING
THE WHOLE THING
INTO A LAKE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
MY WHOLE HOUSE
SHAKES.
SO WHAT?
WELL, THESE PEOPLE...
THEY WANT SOMETHING
SOMETIMES THEY CAN
PLAY PRETTY ROUGH.
Anderson: WHAT ARE
YOU SAYING TO ME?
I WORRY ABOUT YOU.
I LIVE HERE.
THEY DON'T SCARE ME.
YOU'RE SOMETHING,
YOU KNOW THAT?
I'LL SEE YOU.
I'M NOT GOING TO
GIVE UP MY HOME.
[gate creaks]
[floorboard creaks]
[another floorboard creaks]
[thumping]
Mookie [whispering]:
E.T., IS THAT YOU?
[lamp rattles]
[creaking]
[leaves rustling]
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T
THROW THE BALL BACK?
DID YOU COME DOWN
FROM OUTER SPACE?
NO.
HOW COME YOU'VE
GOT A GUN?
ARE YOU
A BAD GUY?
NO.
YOU LIKE BOOBS?
SOMETIMES.
I THINK THEY ARE
TOTALLY GROSS.
MY NAME IS MIKE
BUT EVERYBODY CALLS ME MOOKIE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
SAM.
WELL, SEE YOU TOMORROW,
SAM, OKAY?
I MAY NOT BE HERE TOMORROW.
DON'T YOU KNOW HOW
TO START A FIRE?
YOU HAVE TO LET THE AIR GET IN
OR IT'S NOT GOING TO BURN.
GOING TO COOK SOMETHING?
A STEAK.
LET ME HAVE IT.
I'LL COOK IT FOR YOU.
SHIT.
MOOKIE...
Mookie:
OH, GOD
YOU RUIN
EVERYTHING.
Bree:
I CAN BE HERE.
YOU'RE NOT
THE BOSS OF ME.
THIS IS MY
SISTER, BREE.
THIS IS SAM.
I'M GOING TO
COOK HIM A STEAK.
ME AND MY DAD, WHEN WE'D
GO CAMPING, HE'D LET ME COOK.
YOU DON'T
REMEMBER THAT.
YES, I DO.
YOU WERE
TOO LITTLE.
MOM SAID.
I REMEMBER.
WHERE'S YOUR DAD NOW?
DEAD.
HE HAD A NURDISM.
AN ANEURYSM.
DON'T YOU KNOW
ANYTHING?
HE'S IN THE CEMETERY.
HE'S A SKELETON.
HE IS NOT!
Anderson:
MOOKIE? BREE!
WE GOT TO GO.
BYE, SAM.
HEY!
DON'T TELL ANYONE
YOU SAW ME HERE, OKAY?
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE HE DOESN'T
WANT US TO, ALL RIGHT?
COME ON.
I'M GOING
TO TELL MOM.
YOU BETTER NOT OR I'LL
TELL MOM YOU SMOKE.
I DO NOT!
[cattle lowing]
Bree:
MOMMY?
WHAT HAPPENED
TO HIM?
[screams]
NO!
GET AWAY!
MOMMY...
[metal crashing]
MOM, WHO ARE
THESE GUYS?
STAY DOWN!
OUT OF THE TRUCK.
YOU'RE SCARING
MY CHILDREN!
GET OUT
OF THE TRUCK!
LEAVE THEM ALONE.
SAM!
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I'M THE PARKING ATTENDANT
AND YOU'RE BOTHERING
MY CUSTOMERS.
COME ON.
[yells]
[glass smashes]
OH...
STAY THERE.
WHO ARE YOU?
HE'S MY FRIEND.
HIS NAME IS SAM.
WELL, YOU JUST GOING
TO LET HIM STAND THERE?
WHAT ARE YOU HUNTING?
DEER, MOSTLY.
DEER IS OUT OF SEASON.
YEAH, AND JACKRABBIT.
WE GOT LOTS OF RABBITS, MOM.
I DON'T ALLOW HUNTING
ON MY PROPERTY.
I'M MOSTLY CAMPING.
Anderson: I DON'T ALLOW
CAMPING, EITHER.
WHO WERE THOSE MEN?
COME ON, KIDS, UP TO BED.
Bree: CAN WE STAY UP
FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
NO--
LET'S GO.
WE DIDN'T SAY GOOD NIGHT
TO SAM.
SAY GOOD NIGHT, AND LET'S GO.
BE RIGHT UP.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
QUEBEC.
WHAT DO YOU DO THERE?
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE?
IT'S AN INNOCENT QUESTION.
I'M A LAWYER.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
TO FIGHT LIKE THAT?
LAW SCHOOL.
WHO WERE THOSE GUYS?
POACHERS, I SUSPECT.
THANK YOU FOR THE COFFEE.
GOOD NIGHT, MA'AM.
WAIT...
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
SLEEP IN THE WOODS.
YOU CAN SLEEP IN MY BARN
IF YOU WANT.
NO, THANKS.
YOU CAN HUNT HERE ALL YOU WANT.
I THOUGHT YOU DIDN'T
ALLOW HUNTING.
MAYBE I CHANGED MY MIND.
ARE YOU AFRAID THOSE GUYS
WILL BE BACK?
FORGET IT.
WAIT.
HOW MUCH?
HOW MUCH FOR THE BARN?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO PAY ME.
YOU SURE?
YES.
[voices outside]
[car engine starting]
[wheels spinning]
Anderson:
OUT OF THE WAY.
BREE, I TOLD YOU
ABOUT THAT.
DON'T RUN IN FRONT
OF THE TRUCK.
[kids laugh]
IT'S NOT FUNNY.
BE RIGHT BACK.
YOU DID!
DID NOT!
HI.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
WANT TO WEAR THESE.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
I'M A FRIEND
OF CLYDIE'S.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME,
FRIEND?
SAM.
YOU GOT AN I.D.
IN THOSE PANTS?
SURE.
Clydie:
LONNIE...
I'M NAKED.
DOESN'T BOTHER ME
AT ALL.
WHO IS THIS GUY?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO IS HE?
HE'S MY COUSIN.
FROM QUEBEC.
HE SAID HE WAS
YOUR FRIEND.
MY THIRD COUSIN
ON MY MOTHER'S SIDE.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
LONNIE, THIS
IS RIDICULOUS.
PUT THE GUN DOWN.
SORRY.
CAN I TALK TO YOU
FOR A SECOND?
DO YOU WANT SOME MORE?
YEAH.
THANKS.
CAN YOU PASS THE SALT?
THE OLD BIKE IN THE BARN--
I WOULD LIKE TO BUY IT.
HOW MUCH WILL YOU PAY FOR IT?
I DON'T KNOW-- 200?
THREE.
TAKE IT OR LEAVE IT.
I'LL TAKE IT.
ARE YOU GOING TO GO AWAY ON IT?
I'LL HAVE TO FIX IT FIRST.
IT'S TOO BROKEN
TO BE FIXED.
HE'S GOT
A BIG PENIS.
BREE!
HE DOES.
HE WAS IN THE POND.
HE'S GOT AN AVERAGE PENIS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE I SAW IT.
ALREADY?
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
ABOUT PENISES.
ARE YOU GOING TO SLEEP
IN HER BED?
I SAID
THAT'S ENOUGH!
NO ONE'S GOING TO SLEEP
IN MY BED EXCEPT... ME.
DID YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND?
YOU WANT TO HELP ME?
NO.
IT'S A DAMN
GOOD OFFER--
BETTER THAN YOU WOULD
GET FROM ANYONE ELSE.
I DON'T WANT TO SELL
IT TO ANYONE ELSE.
I DON'T WANT TO SELL IT.
MRS. ANDERSON, I KNOW
YOUR FINANCIAL SITUATION.
FORGIVE ME IF THIS IS
A TRIFLE INDELICATE.
YOU MIGHT NOT BE ABLE TO MAKE
YOUR PAYMENTS.
AND IF YOU CAN'T MAKE
YOUR PAYMENTS
THE BANK WILL BE FORCED
TO FORECLOSE.
THAT'S BECAUSE YOU
BOUGHT INTO THE BANK.
THE BANK NEVER
FORECLOSED
UNTIL YOU CAME HERE.
NEVERTHELESS...
Sam: IT WILL TAKE A MONTH
TO GET THE ORDER TO FORECLOSE.
SHE'D GET A LAWYER.
HE WOULD FILE A WRIT.
THAT WOULD DELAY
A COUPLE OF MONTHS.
YOU WOULD HAVE
TO GO TO TRIAL.
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO
SELL IT, DON'T SELL IT.
FORGIVE ME--
YOU ARE WHO, EXACTLY?
MY COUSIN, SAM.
OH, HELLO.
FRANKLIN HALE.
I'M DELIGHTED
TO MEET YOU.
WELL, THANK YOU FOR
YOUR TIME, MRS. ANDERSON.
GENTLEMEN,
SHALL WE?
BYE.
ASTONISHING, ISN'T IT?
ONE LITTLE WOMAN IN THE MIDDLE
OF A WHEAT FIELD.
AND WHAT IS SHE DOING?
SHE'S FUCKING US UP.
Hale:
MY PROPOSED DEVELOPMENT IS
ONE OF THE LARGEST
OF ITS KIND
AND REPRESENTS A TOTAL
INVESTMENT IN YOUR COMMUNITY
OF NEARLY $1 BILLION.
NOW, WHAT WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT HERE IS NATURAL BEAUTY.
I MUST TELL YOU.
I MEAN, THIS VALLEY OF YOURS--
IT'S ONE OF THE MOST
EXTRAORDINARILY BEAUTIFUL PLACES
I'VE EVER SEEN.
I MEAN, IT'S
QUITE REMARKABLE.
AND I DO WANT
TO ASSURE YOU
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
WOULD MY COMPANY OR MYSELF
EVER DREAM OF DESECRATING
SUCH BEAUTY.
BUT YOU HAVE A LOT OF LAND
WHICH COULD BE USED
MORE EFFICIENTLY
IN A WAY THAT EVERYONE
WOULD BENEFIT.
NOW, I WANT TO GUARANTEE
YOU ALL, EVERY ONE OF YOU...
YOU ALL SHOULD BE ASHAMED
OF YOURSELF.
SELLING OFF YOUR
FAMILY HERITAGE.
Woman: TOM, YOU'RE OUT OF LINE.
SIT DOWN.
I'M NOT SELLING MY LAND.
Hale: PLEASE, LET HIM SPEAK.
HE HAS THE RIGHT TO SPEAK.
PLEASE,
LET HIM SPEAK.
MY DEAR, SIR,
AT FIRST GLANCE
THERE'S BOUND
TO BE OPPOSITION
TO A PLAN LIKE THIS.
BUT YOUR ELECTED
COUNCILPEOPLE
THEY UNDERSTAND THE WISDOM
OF OUR IDEAS
AND THEY HAVE ENDORSED THEM
ENTHUSIASTICALLY.
DON'T MATTER TO ME.
I KNOW THE TACTICS
YOU'RE USING
AND IT WON'T WORK.
NOBODY'S GOING
TO TELL ME
WHAT TO DO WITH MY LAND.
IT'S OKAY, TOM.
THEY CAN'T MAKE US SELL.
Tom:
YOU SURE?
YOU SURE ABOUT
THAT, CLYDIE?
LET'S GO, HONEY.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
[crowd murmurs]
SAM, SAM!
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
WAKE UP!
WHAT?
COME ON!
IT'S OUR NEIGHBOR'S
BARN, SAM.
MOOKIE, WAKE UP
YOUR MOTHER.
HAVE HER CALL
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
NOW, GO!
TOM!
ARE YOU OKAY?
MY HUSBAND'S IN THERE!
STAY BACK!
STAY!
PLEASE,
HELP HIM!
[Tom calling horses]
COME ON!
[neighing]
LET ME HELP.
HAH!
GET THAT ONE.
COME ON!
GO! GO!
COME ON.
LET'S GO!
[shouting at horses]
[coughing]
TOM!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
THE GAS TANKS!
THEY'RE GOING TO GO!
MOVE BACK!
GET BACK!
OH, MY GOD.
THE TANKS ARE
GOING TO BLOW!
GET BACK!
[creaking]
WOW!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
Mookie: I NEVER SAW
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
DID YOU GET BURNED?
Sam:
NO, I WAS LUCKY.
SAM, ARE YOU GOING
TO GO HOME NOW?
YOU'RE GOING
TO STAY?
Sam:
FOR A WHILE.
YOU'RE GOING HOME
SOMETIME, AREN'T YOU?
SAM...
I REALLY DON'T
REMEMBER MY DAD.
NOT LIKE I SAY I DO.
Sam:
IT'S OKAY.
YOU DID GOOD, MOOKIE,
DISCOVERING THE FIRE.
I WASN'T SCARED.
I KNOW.
GOOD NIGHT.
I'VE BEEN OUT HERE ON MY OWN
EVER SINCE MY HUSBAND DIED.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT I COULD
HANDLE WHATEVER CAME UP.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M TELLING YOU THIS.
I DON'T EVEN
KNOW YOU.
SAM...
IS THAT YOUR REAL NAME?
YES.
SOMETIMES YOU
JUST GET TIRED.
I'LL BE OKAY
TOMORROW.
THINGS WILL
BE BETTER.
[horse neighing]
THANKS.
WHAT IS THIS FOR?
THE BRAKES-- WITHOUT IT,
THE BIKE WON'T STOP.
WHAT ABOUT THIS?
Man:
THAT'S GASKET SEALER.
HEY, WHAT KIND OF CAR
YOU WORKING ON?
IT'S NOT FOR A CAR.
A MOTORCYCLE.
IT'S A MOTO... A WHAT?
MOTORCYCLE.
MOTORCYCLE?
YOU'RE NOT FROM
AROUND HERE, ARE YOU?
NEITHER ARE YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT,
NEITHER AM I.
HEY, YOU'RE THAT... THAT
CANADIAN GUY, RIGHT?
PULLED OLD TOM LEWIS
OUT OF HIS BURNING BARN?
YOU'RE THE GUY, RIGHT?
HE SAVED ALL THE HORSES, TOO.
HE DID?
WOW!
THAT MUST HAVE REALLY
BEEN SOMETHING.
SO WHAT KIND?
WHAT KIND OF WHAT?
WHAT ARE WE
TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT KIND OF MOTORCYCLE
ARE YOU WORKING ON?
A TRIUMPH.
TRIUMPH...
THEY DON'T MAKE THEM
LIKE THAT ANYMORE
DO THEY?
NO, THEY DON'T.
Man:
LET'S GO.
YEAH, SEE YOU.
HEY, GOOD LUCK WITH
THE "MOH-TEH-CYCLE."
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE
TO LEARN HOW TO DRIVE
ONE OF THESE?
I'LL SHOW YOU.
I DON'T REALLY
WANT TO KNOW
AS LONG AS YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
DON'T GET CAUGHT,
UNDERSTAND?
I THOUGHT THE LOCAL LAW
WAS TAKEN CARE OF.
HE'S BEEN PAID
BUT I'M NOT SURE
HE'S BOUGHT.
NOT FOR YOU
TO WORRY ABOUT.
WHO'S WORRIED?
GOOD.
THAT YOUR CARD?
YEAH.
HOW'D YOU DO THAT?
MAGIC.
[no film soundtrack]
Bree:
MOMMY, IT THAT YOUR WEDDING?
YUP.
COME ON IN.
WANT SOME COFFEE?
THANK YOU.
Mookie:
SAM, THAT'S MY DAD.
COME ON, LOOK AT HIM.
MOMMY?
WHY IS DADDY CARRYING
YOU LIKE THAT?
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT
THE GROOM DOES--
CARRIES HIS WIFE OFF
SO THEY CAN START
THEIR NEW LIFE TOGETHER.
Bree:
THAT'S ME!
Mookie:
SO LITTLE.
BET HE WAS A GOOD KISSER.
YES, HE WAS.
IT'S VERY BEAUTIFUL HERE.
IT'S THE VALLEY OF THE MOON.
THAT'S WHAT WE CALLED IT.
CAN YOU SMELL
THE VIOLETS?
THERE'S NO PRETTIER SMELL
ON EARTH
THAN THE SMELL OF VIOLETS.
YOU'RE NOT USED TO ALL THIS.
YOU'RE NOT MARRIED, ARE YOU?
USED TO BE, A LONG TIME AGO.
YOU MISS YOUR HUSBAND,
DON'T YOU?
YES.
THERE ARE DAYS
WHEN I MISS HIM VERY MUCH.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SLEEP
IN MY ROOM TONIGHT?
YOU'RE A VERY SPECIAL WOMAN.
I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
[knock at door]
[door opens]
HI.
IT'S LATE, LONNIE.
IT'S NO LATER THAN
IT USUALLY IS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
I JUST DON'T FEEL LIKE IT.
OKAY.
KIDS UP?
NO.
THEN WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU... YOU STILL UPSET
ABOUT THE LEWISES' BARN?
IT'S NOT THAT.
THEN WHAT IS IT?
I DON'T KNOW.
WELL, YOU FIGURE IT OUT,
YOU LET ME KNOW.
GUESS SHE WON'T BE GROWING
MUCH HERE NOW.
[bulldozers chugging
in distance]
[bulldozers chugging,
men laughing]
[cattle lowing]
[cries out in pain]
[metallic screeching]
[groans]
COME HERE!
STRIKE THREE-- YOU'RE OUT.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW MUCH YOU KNOW
ABOUT BUSINESS,
MR. DUNSTON.
THESE THINGS CAN BE
A LITTLE COMPLICATED.
LET ME CLARIFY
THE SITUATION.
WHAT IT COMES
DOWN TO IS THIS:
IF I DON'T HAVE
MRS. ANDERSON'S LAND
BY THE END OF THIS WEEK,
I LOSE MY PERMITS.
IF I LOSE MY PERMITS,
I LOSE THIS DEAL.
IF I LOSE THIS DEAL,
I AM OUT OF BUSINESS.
NOW, IF YOU AND YOUR
LITTLE PISSANT ARMY
CAN'T PERSUADE ONE WOMAN
TO SELL ME HER LAND
I MAY HAVE TO FIND
SOMEONE WHO CAN.
[engine starting]
SO, LONNIE POOLE
WHAT DID YOU
FIND OUT ABOUT HIM?
I KNOW HE'S NOT
HER COUSIN.
GOOD, LON.
LOOK, I DON'T CARE
WHO HE ISN'T.
THIS ASSHOLE'S BEGINNING
TO BOTHER ME.
I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO GO OUT THERE
AND PRESENT HIM
WITH SOME OPTIONS
TO STICKING
AROUND HERE.
LISTEN...
I'D TAKE IT AS
A PERSONAL FAVOR
IF YOU GIVE ME
THE FIRST CRACK AT MAKING
THAT PRESENTATION.
REALLY?
REALLY.
FINE.
[car approaching]
CLYDIE'S NOT HERE.
I KNOW THAT.
I NEVER DID SEE
THAT IDENTIFICATION.
I THOUGHT WE'D BEEN
THROUGH THIS...
STOP RIGHT THERE.
PUT YOUR HANDS UP
AGAINST THE BARN DOOR.
MOVE!
SPREAD 'EM.
ARE YOU
ARRESTING ME?
MAYBE.
WHAT FOR?
I HAVEN'T DECIDED YET.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
LEAVE HER ALONE?
YOU'RE FUCKING IT UP!
FOR EVERYBODY'S SAKE,
JUST GET OUT OF HERE!
IF YOU CARED FOR HER,
YOU WOULD NOT BE DOING THIS.
Bree: THE ITSY, BITSY SPIDER
WENT UP THE WATERSPOUT
DOWN CAME THE RAIN AND
WASHED THE SPIDER OUT...
SAM?
WHAT HAPPENED?
[groans]
DOES THIS HAVE
ANYTHING TO DO
WITH WHAT HAPPENED IN
THE PASTURE LAST NIGHT?
GODDAMN IT.
WHO DID THIS TO YOU?
IT WAS PERSONAL.
WHY DO YOU DO THAT?
WHY DON'T YOU TALK TO ME?
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU'RE HERE.
DO YOU WANT ME TO GO?
YES.
NO.
I DON'T KNOW.
I...
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I WANT.
WHAT I'M DOING.
HI, MOM.
HI, HONEY.
WHERE'S YOUR SISTER?
I DON'T KNOW...
PLAYING SOMEWHERE.
WHERE'S SAM?
HE'S STILL ASLEEP.
UH-UH-- HE'S
NOT IN THE BARN.
HE STAYED IN MY ROOM.
ALL NIGHT?
MM-HM.
ALL RIGHT.
CAN I GO SEE HIM?
NO, HONEY, HE'S REALLY TIRED.
LET HIM SLEEP FOR
A FEW MORE HOURS.
A FEW MORE HOURS?
WHAT DID YOU DO TO HIM?
MOOKIE.
[Bree laughing]
HELLO.
Dunston:
HI.
DOES THIS LITTLE
GIRL BELONG TO YOU?
BREE, WHAT WERE YOU DOING?
I WAS PLAYING.
HE WANTED
TO PLAY WITH ME.
HE CAN PULL A MAGIC
CARD OUT FROM MY EAR.
HE CAN!
MRS. ANDERSON, YOU SHOULDN'T
LET THE CHILD RUN AROUND
LIKE THAT.
DO I KNOW YOU?
NO.
GO INSIDE.
BYE.
BYE-BYE.
WELL, I'M
SURPRISED TO SEE
THAT YOU'RE
STILL HERE.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
YES, I AM.
IF I SEE YOU NEAR
HER OR THE CHILDREN
I'LL KILL YOU.
LOOK.
YOU SEEM LIKE
A SMART FELLOW.
THE WOMAN ISN'T WORTH IT.
AND I'LL TELL YOU,
WHEN PUSH COMES TO SHOVE
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO BE DEALING
WITH SOME LITTLE TIN-BADGE
LOCAL SHERIFF GUY.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE
DEALING WITH ME.
OKAY?
I'LL LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
ME, TOO.
AU REVOIR.
YEAH, FOR NOW.
F.B.I. JUST
LEFT MY OFFICE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
I'M GOING TO DO
EVERYBODY A FAVOR.
LEAVE.
JUST GO SOMEWHERE ELSE.
DO IT RIGHT NOW,
OR I WON'T BE ABLE
TO STOP
WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
WHAT ABOUT CLYDIE?
WHAT ABOUT THIS PLACE?
YOU'RE MAKING IT
MUCH WORSE FOR HER
THAN IT WAS EVER
SUPPOSED TO BE.
IF YOU CARE FOR HER,
YOU'LL GO.
[car engine starts]
[door opens]
I WAS A THIEF.
I DON'T CARE.
THERE WAS A BANK
AND A GUARD GOT SHOT.
SO YOU'RE
A MURDERER.
NO.
A BOY, BILLY--
I TOOK HIM WITH ME
ON A COUPLE OF JOBS.
THE GUARD WAS GOING TO SHOOT ME.
BILLY SHOT HIM FIRST,
AND I WAS TAKEN.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT.
DAMN YOU!
YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO COME INTO OUR LIVES.
YOU HAVE TO GO.
YOU'RE GOING
TO LOSE THIS PLACE.
NO, I AM NOT.
I CAN TAKE CARE OF MYSELF.
I WAS DOING JUST FINE
BEFORE YOU CAME HERE.
I HAVE BEEN ALONE
A LONG TIME.
SO HAVE I.
Mookie:
SAM!
MOOKIE,
YOU'RE IT!
WHOA!
I SAID
YOU'RE IT.
[children laughing]
Sam: CLYDIE, I THOUGHT
IT MIGHT BE EASIER
TALKING TO YOU ON TAPE,
BUT NOW I'M NOT SO SURE.
Hale:
OH, THIS IS EXCELLENT, LONNIE.
THIS IS REALLY EXCELLENT.
WHY DID YOU
LET HIM GO?
YOU'D BE FAMOUS NOW
IF YOU'D COLLARED HIM.
NOW DOESN'T SEEM THE TIME
TO HAVE THIS PLACE CRAWLING
WITH STATE COPS
AND F.B.I.
YOU'RE RIGHT, LONNIE,
QUITE RIGHT.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE
ABOUT YOU, LONNIE--
YOU'RE ALWAYS THINKING.
IT SHOULDN'T
BE TOO DIFFICULT
TO BREAK MRS. ANDERSON'S
RESISTANCE NOW.
I'LL WORK ON THAT
RIGHT AWAY.
THANK YOU, LONNIE.
I DON'T CARE IF OUR LOCAL
SHERIFF SAYS HE'S LEFT TOWN.
I STILL THINK HE'S DANGEROUS.
ME, TOO.
I THINK WE SHOULD TAKE PERSONAL
CHARGE OF THE SITUATION.
Radio broadcaster: ...a little cooler
tonight, dropping down to the 50s
but tomorrow, another sunny day,
so make your plans.
It's going to be
a beautiful day out there...
HEY, PETE.
HEY.
WHAT'S NEW
WITH YOU?
Pete:
NOTHING.
HELLO!
EXCUSE ME
THAT BIKE PARKED OUT FRONT
BELONG TO YOU?
YEAH.
DID YOU RESTORE IT YOURSELF?
IT JUST NEEDED
A LITTLE WORK.
IT WAS NOTHING.
WHERE ARE
YOU FROM?
QUEBEC.
DRIVE HER HERE
ALL THE WAY
FROM CANADA?
YEAH.
YOU MUST BE A GOOD MECHANIC.
Waiter:
COFFEE?
PLEASE.
YOU GOING TO HAVE
ANYTHING TO EAT?
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
WELL, TODAY'S
SPECIAL IS MEATLOAF
OR YOU CAN HAVE
THE REST OF
THAT GUY'S STEAK.
[motorcycle engine starting]
MOOKIE?
Sam:
Clydie...
I thought it might be easier
talking to you on tape.
Now I'm not so sure.
I can never change what I did,
no matter how much I regret it.
Mookie is going to hear
lots of things about me.
Most of them won't be true.
Please say good-bye
to him for me.
Tell him I never meant
for anyone to get hurt
especially him.
[horse whinnying]
[motor starts suddenly]
[gunfire ringing out]
GIDDYUP, GIDDYUP!
[stops motor]
[motorcycle in distance]
[motor starts]
[siren]
SHIT!
[police radio transmissions]
SON OF A BITCH!
GET A CHOPPER NOW!
I WANT HIM TRACKED.
[wind buffeting]
Mookie:
MOM, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
JUST LOCKING UP.
WE NEVER LOCK UP.
WELL, WE'RE
GOING TO START.
MOMMY, ARE YOU
SCARED OF SOMETHING?
NO, HONEY, I'M JUST
BEING CAUTIOUS.
THAT'S DIFFERENT
FROM BEING SCARED.
MY TURN.
[motorcycle engine
in distance]
CLYDIE.
HMM...
KENTUCKY
AVENUE.
WHO HAS THAT?
NOBODY.
OH...
A SIX.
WHERE IS IT?
WHERE AM I?
RUN!!
Man:
GO GET THE KIDS!
RUN!
[Clydie screaming]
[breathing heavily]
[yells]
JOHN, TRY USING
THE STAIRS.
BREE, UPSTAIRS.
John:
OPEN THE DOOR, KIDS.
OPEN THIS GODDAMN DOOR!
I'LL CLIMB OUT
THE WINDOW
AND LOOK FOR HELP.
YOU CAN'T--
YOU'LL FALL.
NO, I WON'T.
I'VE DONE IT BEFORE.
[yells]
MOM!
BREE.
John: THE OTHER LITTLE
SHIT WENT OUT THE WINDOW.
PLEASE DON'T HURT
MY CHILDREN.
Lonnie:
CLYDIE?!
[muffled screaming]
[knocking]
CLYDIE?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
LONNIE!
NOW, GO FIND THE OTHER KID.
Mookie: I'M OVER HERE,
YOU BIG FAT JERK.
[horse whinnying]
COME ON OUT, KID.
COME ON, SON, I--
I WOULDN'T HURT YOU.
[horse whinnies furiously]
[gasping]
[muffled screaming]
SHH!...
SAM!
STAY HERE.
STUPID SHIT.
I'M GONNA KILL
THAT LITTLE SON OF A BITCH.
[groaning]
Dunston:
ALL RIGHT, NO MORE THREATS.
YOU KNOW WHAT
WE'RE HERE FOR.
COME HERE,
SWEETHEART.
WHAT?
I WON'T HURT HER.
PLEASE.
MOMMY, MOMMY.
YOU STAY IN THERE, AND NO NOISE!
I'M SICK OF THIS TOWN,
I'M SICK OF YOU!
I WANT TO GO HOME.
NOW, YOU SIGN
THE CONTRACT!
HERE'S THE PEN!
SIGN THE CONTRACT.
I'M SORRY IT CAME TO THIS.
RIGHT HERE!
[crying]
VERY GOOD.
GO TO HELL.
[spits]
[crying]
GET OUT NOW.
GO!
THIS IS
MY HOUSE!
NO, WE CAN'T LEAVE
BEFORE THE FIRE.
WHAT?
AFRAID I CAN'T TAKE THE RISK.
AL, IF YOU WILL?
[lighter clinks open]
[screaming]
WATCH HER--
WATCH HER!
WHERE IS HE?
[footsteps above]
[creaking above]
[creaking]
[yelling]
[gunshot]
[grunting]
GET UP.
SAM!
LEAVE HIM
ALONE!
[grunting]
SAM!
YOU OKAY?
STAY BEHIND ME.
[rifle being cocked]
SAM!
[gunshot]
AU REVOIR, FUCKER.
[gasping]
Sam:
CLYDIE!
SAM!
DON'T COME
ANY CLOSER.
LET HER GO.
DON'T DO IT.
LET HER GO!
STAY BACK!
[sirens approaching]
THROW
THE GUN DOWN.
THROW THE GUN DOWN NOW!
THROW THE GUN DOWN!
DO IT!
BREE?
MOM!
PUT YOUR HANDS UP.
MY DEAR FELLOW,
I'M FRANKLIN HALE.
I OWN HALF THIS...
TURN AROUND
AND FACE THE HOUSE.
THERE'S AN ESCAPED
CONVICT IN THERE!
TURN AROUND.
DO IT!
GO! YOU CAN
STILL GET AWAY.
NO.
Officer:
SAM GILLARD...
THE HOUSE IS SURROUNDED.
COME OUT WITH YOUR HANDS
ABOVE YOUR HEAD.
WHY DO THEY
WANT YOU?
YOU DIDN'T DO
ANYTHING WRONG.
A LONG TIME AGO,
I DID SOME THINGS
I WAS NOT SUPPOSED TO DO.
ARE THEY GOING
TO TAKE YOU TO JAIL?
YES.
I DON'T WANT
YOU TO GO.
I GOT TO GO.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO.
GOOD-BYE, MOOKIE.
GOOD-BYE,
MOOKIE.
GOOD-BYE, BREE.
BYE, SAM.
ARE YOU COMING BACK?
I'LL FIND A WAY.
SOMEHOW I'LL FIND A WAY
TO COME BACK TO YOU.
NO MATTER
HOW LONG IT TAKES
WE'LL BE HERE.
I KNOW.
I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
YOU SAVED A LOT
OF LIVES HERE.
THAT OUGHT TO COUNT
FOR SOMETHING.
[police radio transmissions]
LET'S GO.
SAM!
GOOD-BYE,
MY FRIEND.
BYE, SAM.
GO.
YOU BASTARD!
DO YOU KNOW WHO I AM?
[thump]
[grunting]
I KNOW WHAT YOU ARE.